University of Connecticut
© 2005 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, Loeb Awards for Distinguished Business and Financial Journalism Records.
1957-1961.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut.
2 linear feet.
MSS19710002
The Loeb Awards were designed to reward authors whose writings in business and finance report explain the mechanics, strengths, problems, and values of American capitalism and enterprise. The Advisory Board of the Loeb Awards at the University of Connecticut sought those meritorious journalistic contributions which combined superior writing, clarity, accuracy, and analysis of subjects of import to the growth and development of the American enterprise system.
History
The Loeb Awards for Distinguished Business and Financial Journalism were established in 1957 by Gerald M. Loeb, author of The Battle for Investment Survival and a senior partner with E.F. Hutton and Company.
The Loeb Awards were designed to reward authors whose writings in business and finance report explain the mechanics, strengths, problems, and values of American capitalism and enterprise. The Advisory Board of the Loeb Awards at the University of Connecticut sought those meritorious journalistic contributions which combined superior writing, clarity, accuracy, and analysis of subjects of import to the growth and development of the American enterprise system.
The Loeb Awards Advisory Board appointed two panels of judges, one for newspaper awards and one for magazine awards. The judges represented the fields of journalism, business, and education. Upon their recommendation, the Trustees of the University of Connecticut made the final selection of winners. During his tenure as President of the University of Connecticut, Homer D. Babbidge, Jr. served as Chairman of the Loeb Awards Advisory Board. Other members of the board included Governor John Dempsey, Gerald M. Loeb, and Robert O. Harvey, Dean of the School of Business Administration at the University of Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The Loeb Awards for Distinguished Business and Financial Journalism Records (1957-1971) consist of two linear feet of material. There are limited administrative records (1 folder, 1964-1971), a collection of Award Dinner Programs (1961-1971), and a scrapbook of news clippings and photographs (1957-1963). The bulk of the collection consists of the winning entries in the Loeb Awards competition. The articles are arranged chronologically by year, and are subdivided into the categories: Award Winners, Achievement Winners, and Special Awards. Special Awards were not given every year. Except in 1970-1971, there were two Award winners each year, one for newspaper writing and one for magazine writing. In 1970-1971, a third Award category for editorials was established. The Achievement Awards were of lesser distinction, and usually four of these were given annually. There are no copies of articles for the 1969 awards, although awards were given.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of records pertaining to the University's history, as well as associated programs and activities. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Loeb, Gerald M.
Subjects:
Journalism--Awards.; Capitalism--United States--20th century.; Finance--United States--20th century.; Business--Communication.
Document Types:
Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.
Occupations:
Institution of Higher Education.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The materials were transferred by the President's Office.
Acquisition Information
The materials were transferred by the President's Office.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Records, 1957-1961
  - Administrative Material, 1964-1971 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Award Dinner Programs, 1961-1971 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1957-1963 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Award winners, 1958 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - David Steinberg
    - Werner Renberg
  - Achievement winners, 1958 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Leslie Gould
    - George Arris and Joseph Goodrich
    - T.A. Wise
    - J.A. Livingston
  - Award winners, 1959 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Nate White
    - Ernest Haveman
  - Achievement winners, 1959 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Donald I. Rogers
    - Jay Edgerton
    - Murray J. Rossant
    - Alexander O. Stanley
  - Award winners, 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Nate White
    - John A. Conway
  - Achievement winners, 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - J.A. Livingston
    - John L. Fletcher
  - Achievement winners, 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Edward T. Townsend and Richard Larkin
    - Gurney Breckerfield
  - Award winners, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - Staff, Wall Street Journal
    - Leonard Silk
  - Achievement winners, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Lee M. Cohn
    - Sidney Fish
    - Hobart Rowen and Sandford Brown
    - Tait Trussel
  - Award winners, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Robert E. Bedingfield
    - Richard Austin Smith
  - Achievement winners, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Christina Kirk
    - Ben Shifman
    - John Chamberlain
    - Daniel Friedenberg
  - Award winners, 1963 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - David R. Jones
    - Sandford Brown
  - Achievement winners, 1963 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Robert E. Nichols
    - Hugh R. McEvers
    - Gilbert H. Clee
    - Robert W Murray, Jr.
  - Award winners, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 17)
    - Robert E. Nichols
    - John Brooks
  - Achievement winners, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 18)
    - Lee M. Cohn
    - Darden Chambliss
    - Mat Ways
    - John Maughan
  - Award winners, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 19)
    - Edwin L. Dale, Jr.
    - Lee Silberman
  - Achievement winners, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 20)
    - Daniel M. Friedenberg
    - Thomas W. Bush
    - Clem Morgello
    - Staff, House and Home
    - Special Award, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 21)
    - Leslie Gould
  - Award winners, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 22)
    - Ross M. Robertson
    - Charles E. Silberman
  - Achievement winners, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - Frank H. Weir
    - Peter S. Nagan
    - Leonard S. Silk
    - Gilbert Burck
  - Award winners, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - David R. Francis
    - Max Ways
  - Achievement winners, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - Sidney Fish
    - Staff, The Wall Street Journal
    - Leonard Silk
    - Staff, Business Week
  - Award winners, 1968 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - Richard A. Nenneman
    - Michael Laurence
  - Achievement winners, 1968 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - John A. Prestbo
    - Lee Silberman
    - Peter P. Gabriel
    - John K. Jessup
  - Special Awards, 1968 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - Nicholas Molodovsky
    - Milton Friedman, Paul Samuelson and Henry Wallich
  - Award winners, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - Leland B. DuVall
    - John F. Lyons
    - Patricia Shontz
  - Achievement winners, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - James P. Gannon
    - Morton C. Paulson
    - Rich Thomas
    - Gilbert Burck
    - Alan Abelson
    - E. B. Weiss
  - Award winners, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - Joseph A. Livingston
    - Chris Welles
    - Philip Breer
  - Achievement winners, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - Richard E. Rustin
    - John F. Laurence
    - Paul E. Steiger
    - Ephraim A. Lewis
    - Carol J. Loomis
    - Harold Chucker
    - Leonard S. Silk